本字幕由 ShinY 深影字幕组 原创翻译制作
深影字幕组论坛地址 http://shinybbs.com
翻译： 媚子 王老猫 Floralin fanfan JoJo
校对： 小坏玩意儿   后期： 深影后期组
法律面前并非人人平等
There is no equality before the law.
前情提要
那是我的第一条真理
That is my first truth.
离我姐妹远点
Stay away from my sister.
正因为她在 你在码头才没被打倒
It's only cos of her you're not face-down in the harbour.
为什么这么敌对
Why all the hostility?
刚才外面的那个男人...
The man you were with outside...
别再和他说话了
You must not talk to him.
- 我不喜欢这里 - 你别无选择
- I don't like it here. - You don't have an alternative.
那个男人让你处境危险
You're in danger from that man.
我选择了你
I have chosen you.
我想要人们知道我为何如此行事
I want people to know why I'm doing this.
是他 又开始行动了
It's him, it's started.
老人有什么用
What good are old people?
他们不事生产
They do not produce,
所以我们让他们孤独死去
so we leave them to die alone.
死亡人数为十四人
The confirmed death toll is 14,
但警方预示人数可能还会上升
but police are warning that this may rise.
现在联合犯罪局局长助理吉瑞・布莱恩特
I'm now joined by Assistant Chief Constable Gerry Bryant
就在我身旁
from the Unified Crime Directorate.
局长助理先生
Assistant Chief Constable,
如果这起案件的凶手
if this is the work of the killer
与在欧洲隧道杀死两名受害者的是同一个人
who left two victims in the Eurotunnel,
那我们就该考虑这案件的严重性了
then we are looking at a serious escalation.
是的 目前为止
Yes, although as yet,
我们还没有确定它们是否有关联
we have no confirmation to that effect.
但我向市民们保证 我们已经计划...
But I can assure the public that we've drafted in...
所有的受害者都服用了同一种吗啡类止痛药
All the victims have the same morphine-based painkillers.
那司机呢
What about the driver?
没有 吹嘘罢了 他是清白的
No, usual blurb. He's clean.
所以如果那些药物被污染了 就是在别处作案
So, if the drugs were contaminated, it was done elsewhere
然后它们被放在面包车里
and they were placed on the van.
- 我来探望我姐妹 - 我跟你说了
- I've come to see my sister. - I've told you already,
一次只能有一位访客
just one visitor at a time.
他来了
Here he is.
正人君子来了
Voucher Man.
抱歉 伙计
Sorry, pal.
你错过了人工呼吸和胸部按摩
You missed the mouth-to-mouth and chest massages.
你能让这男的出去吗
Will you have this man removed from this room?
- 他很可能是凶手 - 是 我是凶手
- He probably caused this. - Yeah, course I did.
她打给谁了
Who did she phone?
谁在她需要的时候帮她了 是我救的她
Who did what was needed? I saved her.
你却没做到
You couldn't do that.
什么都做不了
You can't do anything.
你会为我能做的事而惊讶
You'll be surprised what I can do.
保安 306病房
Security, room 306.
斯蒂芬 你...
Stephen, just...
走吧
Just go.
走吧... 等... 再回来
Just...go and come back when...
斯蒂芬... 斯蒂芬...
Stephen... Stephen...
斯蒂芬
Stephen!
四号房
Number four.
到了 哈瑞特・斯通 一样的药 却没症状
There we go. Harriet Stone. Same drugs, no symptoms.
一整批都有毒怎么她还能没事
How did she remain immune if it was a poison batch?
她没聋
She's not deaf.
为何不进来问她呢
Why don't you come in and talk to her?
- 书好看吗... 哈瑞特 - 有点悲伤
- So, is it a good book...Harriet? - Hmm, a little sad.
- 是吗 - 是 不过没事 我喜欢悲伤的
- Is it? - Yes, but that's all right, I like sad.
- 是啊 悲伤也挺好的 不是吗 - 是
- Yeah, sad's all right, isn't it? - Yeah.
- 对书来说 还有音乐 - 是
- In books anyway. And tunes. - Hmm, yes.
还有什么
So, what else?
关于苏珊娜还有什么想说的
What else can you tell us about Susanna?
- 她不开心 - 不开心吗
- She's not happy. - No?
- 为什么 - 我也不知道原因 直觉而已
- Why not? - I don't know why, I just know.
她帮你拿药
She gives you your medication?
药挺好的 是啊
For all the good it does. Yes.
- 你是法国人 - 是的
- Are you French? - Yes.
我很想再去一次法国
I'd love to go to France again.
但不可能了
But I never will.
是的 可能旅游对现在的你来说
No, the journey would probably be
太困难了
too difficult for you now.
喂
Yep.
苏珊娜・博蒙特在医院
Susanna Beaumont's in hospital.
可怜的苏
Oh, poor Suze.
她朗读的声音很好听
She has a lovely reading voice, you know?
我不知道你想说什么
I don't understand your point.
她自己说
She said herself
她没希望再去法国了
it was unlikely she would see France again.
- 所以你赞同了 - 是
- And you agreed? - Yes.
但是也许她不想...
But maybe she didn't want...
不好意思 你是觉得她还能再去法国吗
I'm sorry, do you think she will see France again?
不是 但那不是重点
No, but that's not the point.
你为何不直接说
Why didn't you just say,
"你都快进棺材了 奶奶"
"You'll be in the graveyard soon, Grandma."
因为我没这样想
Because it's not what I was thinking.
有时你只用说好话 警察
Sometimes you just need to say the right thing. Police.
不要说永远 类似这样的
Never say never, that kind of thing.
那应该会说出很白痴的话
That would have been a really dumb thing to say.
好吧 苏珊娜・博蒙特
Okay. Susanna Beaumont.
给她打了镇定剂 还是很难受
She's sedated, still in a lot of pain.
还有 今天早上他兄弟来了
And there was a bit of a scene this morning
发生了点小插曲
with her brother.
什么小插曲
What kind of scene?
她兄弟很难对付 让她很不安
An ugly one which left her very disturbed.
他走之前还打了护士
He struck a nurse before leaving.
他叫什么
What's his name?
他叫斯蒂芬・博蒙特
Eh, it was Stephen Beaumont,
法定近亲
he's the official next of kin.
是他送她来的
Did he bring her in?
不 她自己坐救护车来的
No, she was on her own in the ambulance.
- 她现在在哪儿 - 在旁边的房间
- Where is she now? - Er, in a side room.
所以她跟那些老人一样都吃了同一种药
So, she ate the same poison as the old people?
是的 但因为她更年轻强壮
Yeah, but she's younger and fitter,
所以情况比较乐观
so her body's better able to deal with it.
这不能解释它是怎么到这儿来的 不是吗
It doesn't explain how it got there, does it?
她刚稳定下来 别跟她说话
She's through there.Don't try and talk to her.
你觉得是她干的吗
Do you think she did it?
先毒死十四名老人
Poisoned 14 old people
然后假装用一样的方式自杀
and then tried to kill herself the same way?
不是
No.
事实上是用鸦片类止痛
Given the fact that it was an opiate-based pain relief,
我认为她偷了哈瑞特・斯通的药
I think she was stealing Harriet Stone's medication.
安全地回到了吗啡姐的怀抱
Safely back in the arms of Sister Morphine.
"亲爱的斯蒂芬 学校..."
"Dear Stephen, how is..."
"亲爱的斯蒂芬"
"Dear Stephen."
"学校怎么样"
"How is school?"
"妈妈说你讨厌上学 她走的时候你还哭了"
"Mummy says you hate it and cried when she left you."
"记住 你是我的至爱"
"Remember, I love you more than anybody.
"姐妹 苏"
"Your sister, Suze."
- 她没寄出去 - 是的
- She never sent it? - No.
好吧 我们先去看看她的公寓
Okay, let's take a look at her flat.
查克斯 帮我查查斯蒂芬・博蒙特行吗
Chuks, run a check on Mr Stephen Beaumont, would you?
# 到我怀里来 #
Venez dans mes bras
# 靠近我 亲爱的 #
Closer to me, dear
# 让我自己 #
Donnez-vous moi
# 抛开所有恐惧 #
Set aside all fear
# 一根红线 缠绕永远 #
Restons enlaces pour l'ternit
# 是的 你是我的 #
Yes, you shall be mine
# 直到地老天荒 #
Till the end of time
隧道谜案 第一季第三集
我不知道斯蒂芬要对我们做些什么
I don't know what Stephen's going to do with us?
他把我们带到这个脏房子还有...
He brought us to this dirty cottage and...
帮帮我 求你了
You have to help me, please.
我想离开这里 想去伦敦
I want to leave, I want to go to London.
我需要钱...快点
I need money...quickly.
你在哪儿 哪个区域
Where are you? What part?
我不知道 有个电话亭 红色的
I don't know. Phone box, it's red.
还有两匹马在牧场上
There is a field with two horses.
房子什么颜色
And what colour are the horses?
有一栋是棕色的...
Um, there is one brown...
另一栋是黑的 带白色斑点
and the other one is black with white spots.
我开玩笑呢 亲爱的 你在哪条街
I'm joking, babe. What street are you on?
我... 我看不到任何标志 什么都没有
I... I can't see any signs, there's nothing.
无名街... 旁边有匹马
Where the streets have no name... near a horse.
因为这样我才不常去乡下旅游
That's why I don't normally travel the countryside.
我想起来了 有个酒吧
I see, there is a pub.
我们经过一条路
We passed on the road.
叫狐狸和什么的
Um, the Fox and something.
猎犬
Hounds?
弗金 黑尔
Firkin? Hare?
猎犬 还有那房子在路的同一边
Hounds, and the house is on the same side of the road,
有一点远
just a little bit further.
好
Okay.
我会用导航仪在荒郊中心兜一圈的
I'll search through the middle of nowhere on my GPS.
玩一下午的猎狗追狐
An afternoon of playing Fox and Hounds
把去伦敦的火车票给你
gets you a train ticket to London.
再给点零花钱去参观白金汉宫
Some extra pocket money to visit Buckingham Palace.
我不明白为什么...
I don't know why...
我从没干过这个 不知道怎么...
I've never done this before, I don't know how...
你会没事的 顺其自然就好
You'll be fine. Just go with the flow.
我来帮你介绍
I'll do the introductions.
你只要保证别让孩子在周围 好吗
You make sure the kid's not around now, yeah?
别让他看见我
Don't even let him see me.
她最后一通电话是打给安东尼・沃尔什的
Last number called from her mobile was to Anthony Walsh.
- 他是... - 吉玛・柯万的皮条客
- As in...? - Gemma Kirwan's pimp.
他可不只这一个营生
And not the only string to his bow.
听说他最近毒品卖得风生水起
He's stated slinging a lot of meth recently, I hear.
显然没卖给苏珊娜
Yeah, not to Susanna though.
我们认为她的药是偷来的 不是买的
We think she was stealing drugs, not buying them.
她兄弟那边有什么消息吗
Anything on the brother?
斯蒂芬・博蒙特 居无定所
Stephen Beaumont, no fixed abode.
在慈善机构帮助寻求庇护者
Works for some charity helping asylum seekers
和其他类似人员
and the like.
- "类似人员" - 别问 头儿
- "And the like?" - Don't start, boss,
我还没吃早餐呢
I haven't even had breakfast yet.
对了 他出国了
Anyway, he's out of the country.
- 去哪儿了 - 不清楚
- Where? - Don't know,
只听到他那可笑的手机彩铃
just heard the funny ringtone on his mobile.
也许在罗马尼亚
Probably in Romania,
寻找其他可以带回来提供帮助的人
rounding up a few more he can bring over to help.
给慈善机构打电话 问他什么时候回国
Phone the charity, find out when he's due back in the UK.
- 让他联系我们 - 好的
- Get him to give us a shout. - Cool.
我把事情记在脑子里
I put things in rooms.
很好
Fine.
就是个简单的记忆装置
It's just a simple memory device.
管用吗
How does that work?
我想象脑子里有一个房子
I have this imaginary house in my head.
里面有很多房间
With many rooms.
我把想要记住的事情分门别类放在各个房间里
I put things I want to remember into parts of the house
这样我就知道到哪里去找它们
so I know where to look for them.
睡不着的时候 我会走进去
Sometimes when I can't sleep, I walk through it,
看看每个房间
look into each room.
它是什么样的
What does it look like, your house?
你必须自行想象你的房子
You have to make your own house,
否则不管用
otherwise it doesn't work.
是建立在一个真实房子的基础上吗
Is it based on a real house?
那里的警察什么样
So what were the cops like?
有个法国警察
There was a French detective,
她有点古怪 但你会喜欢的
she was a bit weird, but you would.
那个英国警察嘛 他...
And then the English one and he...
- 很不喜欢我 - 不是吧...
- He really didn't like me. - No...
对你的摇钱树
Oh! Little bit more respect
尊重点好吗 乔诺
for your golden goose, please, Johnno.
毕竟真杀选了我作联系对象
I mean, TT did choose me to communicate with.
- 真杀 - 对 "真理杀手"
- TT? - Yeah, "Truth Terrorist".
昨晚想出来的 不赖吧
Came up with it last night. Good, hey?
是啊 也许我们应该谨慎点
Yeah, we should perhaps be a little careful
别过度美化这个疯子
about glamorising the mad bastard.
对啊 这样能增加
Oh, yeah, that's a strategy
我们的线上点击率
that's going to boost our online hit-rate.
听着 我们得到了一个
Look, we've got an in
数年来最具爆炸性的新闻
with one of the biggest news phenomenons in years.
是啊
Yeah.
- 喂 - 丹尼
- Yeah? - Danny.
我的第二个真理才刚刚开始
My second truth has only just begun.
没人在乎做出牺牲
Nobody cares about people who made sacrifices,
辛苦工作 为国家效力的人
worked hard, or served their country.
一旦社会不再需要他们
Once society no longer needs them, they're abandoned...
他们就会被无情抛弃 自生自灭
to slow and lonely death.
什么 所以你要帮他们个忙吗
What, so you're doing them a favour?
我是说 无意冒犯 伙计 但你怎么知道
I mean, no offence, mate, but how do you know
他们不喜欢坐在自己的尿上
they weren't happy sitting in their own piss
看便宜货大作战呢
and watching Bargain Hunt?
便宜货大作战:英国电视节目
谁赋予你评断他人生命意义的权力呢
I mean, who appointed you judge of what their lives meant?
听着 你说你的第二条真理已经开始了
Look, you said that your second truth has begun?
很好 你不光能说会道
Good. You listen as well.
这不只是在英国才有的问题
This is not just a problem in Britain.
好的 所以呢
Okay, so?
不久我们就会知道
Soon we will see how much
法国的老英雄们有多受重视了
old heroes are cared for in France.
等等 别着急
你想玩球吗
我们玩你的小球吧
给你解开绳子 玩吧
我知道你花钱是要玩粗野点的
I know you paid for a bit of rough and tumble
但是... 别太过了 好吗
but...don't take it too far, yeah?
几个耳光就好
Couple of slaps.
特别说一下 别搞窒息
Bit of verbal, no air locking.
对蒂娜温柔点 好吗
And go easy on Tina, yeah?
你会玩得很爽的
It's got a kick to it.
来吧
Come on.
不
No.
No!
博蒙特先生 我是诺思伯恩警局的
Mr. Beaumont, this is DC Chuks Akinade
查克斯・阿金内德探员
of Northbourne Police.
你回国后能给我打个电话吗
Could you give me a call when you're back in the country?
百货公司的政策向来都是起诉
The policy of the department store is always to press charges.
然而 鉴于她的年龄
However, in the light of her age
和初犯的事实
and the fact that this is the first time...
那是个误会
It was a mistake.
试试 "我这样做是因为朋友的唆使"
Try, "I did it because my friends bullied me into it."
她没有朋友
She hasn't got any friends.
优秀的人总是与众不同的 甜心
The top was the wrong colour anyway, sweetheart.
想引人注意
You need something to draw attention
就用你这双可爱的大眼睛啊
to those lovely big eyes.
那是遗传我爸的
I get them from my dad.
好吧
All right.
别再让我在这里看到它们就好
Well, just don't let me see them round here any more.
告诉我惩罚是什么吧
So tell me what my punishment is?
除了不能和爸爸而是和你生活以外
Apart from having to live with you and not Dad.
我们知道他是谁吗
还不清楚 但是会有人认出来的
这个真理是关于老人的
凶手提到过法国老英雄
他这次最好没用我们的服务器
没用
他用的是洋葱路由器
用户能随意发布文件而不会被追踪到发布路径
有图层加密技术
最近一次我们追踪到的地址是摩尔多瓦的某处
爱丽丝去哪儿了
跟夏洛克・福尔摩斯在隧道里
别怕
Don't be scared.
他是匹好马
He's a nice horse.
就这样
That's it.
他会喜欢的 给你
Oh, he'll like that. There you go.
好孩子 吃光它
There's a good boy. Eat up.
你家在哪儿
Where you come from?
你妈妈呢 宝贝
Where's your mummy, sweetheart?
一切还好吗
Is everything okay?
我只是...
It's just...
觉得他不应该
I just thought he shouldn't be in the field
独自在牧场呆着
on his own like that.
已临近搜索区域 开启热成像
看起来希望不大 但是有几处热源
我们先大范围搜索 然后对异常情况放大影像
收到 猎鹰一号 完毕
来看看这个
你好 卡尔
Hello, Karl.
让・克劳德・戴尔普兰克
Jean-Claude Delplanque.
76岁 退伍军人
76 years old, retired soldier.
两小时前出现在网上
Appeared online two hours ago.
76岁 状态不错 比英国那个受害者好多了
76, in good shape. Better than the English victims.
谁认出他了吗
Who identified him?
凯瑟琳・勒克莱尔
Catherine Leclerc.
一个在港口流动厨房工作
A coordinator from one of the soup kitchens
为移民们提供食物的协调员
that works with immigrants in the port.
他去那里干什么
What does he do there?
喝汤 和移民们聊天
Drinks soup, talks to the immigrants.
为什么是他
Why him?
凶手有他的理由
He'll have a reason.
他好像在一个旧工厂里
It looks like he's in an old industry unit.
我们安排了带有热成像的直升机
We've got helicopters with thermal-imaging equipment
负责搜索工业区的废弃建筑
searching abandoned buildings in the industrial zones.
他住在哪里
Where does he live?
鉴证科已经到了那里
Forensics are there already.
正在附近搜索和走访调查
Have a look around and talk to the neighbours.
网民很快会注意到直播视频
Even the internet. He will soon have the audience he needs.
请给我接辖区办公室
是的 现在
硬汉风格
什么
Mm? Pardon?
硬汉风格
Tough guy style.
禁止进入 女士
没有床
No bed.
让我进去 否则我起诉你
你是哪位
凯瑟琳・勒克莱尔 我在码头的救济站工作
凯瑟琳・勒克莱尔 你是那个认出...
Catherine Leclerc. You're the woman that identified...
我不懂英语
我只是来确认你们不会翻乱这里
- 顺便看看福煦 - 福煦
他的宠物狗
什么东西
What's est le chien?
你跟让・克劳德很熟吗
他不太合群 以前在军队待过
所以给狗起了这么个蠢名字
他给移民上基础法语课
他有社会良知吗
我不这样认为 没有
他认为移民应该更加融入这里
尽管对他们的文化不太感兴趣
他的房东很差劲 所以我才来帮他一些忙
我之前跟房东闹过矛盾
他想让克劳德离开
喂
好的 我们马上到
有人可能目击了绑架过程
Someone may have seen the abduction.
法国共产主义者
Communist Party of France.
我敢打赌
I put my house on it.
因为他在救济站工作
Because he works in a soup kitchen.
是的 不仅如此 小时候我们去过人文节
Yeah, well, not just that. Spot them a mile off.
一公里之外就能看见他们
We used to go L'Humanit festivals when we were kids.
当时他在这里遛狗
遛狗时被绑架的
目击者称是一辆没见过的面包车
他被吓坏了 没法说清细节
他还以为是警察在工作 所以就离开了
好的
Okay.
鉴证科对泰瑟枪做了鉴定
- 然后呢 - 查不出型号
绑匪掩盖了痕迹
硬币而已
Finder's keepers.
我们唯一的目击者在这
Here's our only witness.
说说你看见了什么
Anyone speak his language?
你会说英语吗
Parlez-vous anglais?
让・克劳德遭到电击时 狗还套着狗绳
He was still on his leash when Jean-Claude got tasered.
- 是的 - 可能也就是五米的距离
- Yeah. - Probably within a 5-meter range.
你有梳子吗
没有
你们有梳子吗
Do either of you have a comb?
没有
No.
猜测很大胆
That's a long shot.
不是吧
No.
是碱火焰电离检测器标签
It's an AFID tag.
绑匪在下手之前
The dog must have run off
这条狗先逃跑了
before he had a chance to get him.
干得好
That's good.
太好了
That's very good.
绑匪疏忽了这点 太好了
He's made a mistake. That's very good.
你想干什么 为什么我会在这里
你究竟想干什么
你有什么目的
回答我
为什么把我带到这里
告诉我...
还是没消息
我们扩大了搜索范围
列出了一份空仓库的名单
美国已经发生三起信件炸弹事件
While inevitably people have drawn comparisons
三人遇害
with the Unabomber,
人们难免会联想到
whose letter bombs killed three people
智能炸弹
in the United States.
今天邀请到的是
I'm joined now by
心理学家及学者米里亚姆・英吉利
psychologist and academic Miriam English.
一个简单的问题...他为什么要做这些事
A very simple question... Why is he doing this?
好 继续 米利亚姆
Yeah, go on, Miriam.
为我们揭开真相吧
Give us the lowdown.
专家们的福音
Payday for the experts, eh?
女儿怎么不回自己房间睡
Why aren't the girls in their bed?
- 我把床在易趣网上卖了 - 干得好
- I sold them on eBay. - Good move.
她们睡我们的床
They're in our bed.
这得感谢你的大儿子
You can thank your eldest son.
为什么 他干什么了
Why, what's he'd done now?
他给妹妹们看了网上绑架的直播视频
He showed them that web bite with the kidnapped man,
她们现在显然是吓坏了
so obviously now they're too scared to sleep in their room.
- 你干什么 - 我干什么
- What's up with you? - What's up with me?
你在玩什么
What are you playing at?
干嘛给汉娜和玛雅看那个恐怖的视频
Showing Hannah and Maya all that scary stuff?
大家都在看 都在谈论啊
Everyone's watching it, everybody's talking about it.
- 这是真实的 - 大家起码都十岁了吧
- It's reality. - Everybody isn't under ten years old.
我不是故意的
I didn't show it to them.
她们像平常一样来捣蛋
They just came in here bothering me as usual
不小心看到的
and then they saw it.
那你更应该注意一点
Well, you should be more careful.
学会你的教育方法还需要点时间
It might take me a while to learn your parenting skills.
你提到的那个记者 丹尼・希勒
That journalist you mentioned, Danny Hillier.
大家都在看他的博文
Everyone's reading his stuff.
很好
Great.
称他为真杀 真理杀手
Calls him TT. The "Truth Terrorist."
大家都在谈论真杀的行为
People are talking about what TT's doing.
关于正义 老人
The thing about justice, the old people.
你可以质疑
You can say what you like,
但起码比八卦名人的绯闻
but it's better than chatting about
强多了
all that celebrity shit.
现在我宁愿汉娜和玛雅
Well, right now I'd rather that Hannah and Maya's reality
只是反应过激了
was a little more anthropomorphic fare.
什么
What?
小女孩们
Peppa Pig.
保证她们远离你的电脑
Keep them away from your computer.
是爱丽丝・瓦塞尔曼吗
Is that Elise Wassermann?
我能打声招呼吗
Can I say bonjour?
查克斯
Chuks.
什么时候
When?
好的 我马上到
Right. I'll come now.
- 你还在吗 - 在 刚才我爸又来烦我了
看这个
是他的枪吗
马丁・戴伯里克 他声称枪不见了
一年前的事 我记得
他是名糟糕的警察
这份陈述不够充分 但他似乎从未...
奥利弗吗
戴伯里克
你们要干嘛
不是...住手
你偷了哈瑞特・斯通的止痛药
You were stealing Harriett Stone's painkillers.
她还好吗
Is she all right?
很好
Yeah.
托你的福 让她痛苦不堪
Thanks to you leaving her in agony while you fed your habit.
我的生活一团糟
My life was such a mess.
我之前是个名人 你知道吗
I used to be somebody, you know?
我以前是电影明星的经纪人
I used to do PR for film stars.
大部分还都是大牌
Most of them are right cunts.
其余的也不错
Some of them are all right.
但是我不在乎 一味地...
I didn't care, just...
聚会 吸毒 去俱乐部
parties, drugs and clubs.
现在我还记得那种感觉
I remember the smell of it.
人家过去叫我性感苏
People used to call me Sexy Suze.
我跟明星在厕所乱搞
I fucked film stars in toilets.
但好事不长久...
But like all good things...
别笑话我
Don't laugh at me.
我没有笑你
I'm not laughing at you.
后来是怎么结束的
So how'd you end up?
后来一切都开始走下坡路
Things just started to go wrong.
我兄弟在这里吗
Is my brother here yet?
不在
No.
你和斯蒂芬关系好吗
Are you close to Stephen?
他知道你在哪儿吗
Does he know where you were?
为什么这么问
Why?
好奇而已
Just curious.
他想拯救世界
He wants to save the world.
是吗
Does he?
斯蒂芬跟我说过他的眼睛
Stephen told me about his eyes.
谁的
Whose eyes?
你知道现在斯蒂芬在哪里吗
Do you know where Stephen might be now?
我不舒服
I was sick.
鱼的鲜血让我恶心
Sick-sick because of the blood on the fish.
他们在船底猛打鱼的脑袋
They were hitting their heads on the bottom of the boat.
行了
That's enough.
你遗失的泰瑟枪在一起绑架案件中被使用
所以呢
要是好人捡到他们会上交的
你根本没有把它放在车顶上
事实上 你根本没有遗失它
别搞笑了
我为什么要编这么蠢的话骗你
我因为这事被开除了
还有可卡因
一个罪犯跟踪警察
希望他蠢到会把泰瑟枪落在车顶
你觉得这可能吗
我已经付出过代价了
随你怎么想 我不在乎
你结婚了吗
有关系吗
你老婆知道你用手机应用找男人吗
你的介绍上说"不能留宿"
那么我想她应该不知道
就算她知道也不会比你
现在涉嫌一起连环谋杀案更重要
你最好实话实说
他老婆走了
His wife was away.
他最后跟几个
He ended up with some guys in a flat
不知道住哪里的男人在公寓里
whose address he can't remember.
他一醒来...
And when he woke up...
我知道了 他还是想不起来
I see where it's going. So, no idea?
他真的想不起来
He honestly can't remember a thing
关于酗酒 吸毒 性交的任何事情了
about it: the alcohol, drugs, sex...
而且这些事情发生在一年前
And it all happened a year ago.
你看过酒吧里面的闭路电视没有
You checking the bar's CCTV?
- 看过了 - 有什么发现
- Yeah. - High hopes?
没有
No.
苏珊娜・博蒙特刚刚醒了 我试图和她谈话
Susanna Beaumont was awake. I managed to speak to her.
- 发现什么吗 - 我不知道
- Anything interesting? - I don't know.
好的 明天早上再和你说吧
Okay. I'll speak to you in the morning.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
做晚餐
Making dinner.
夜晚的医院
Hospitals at night, eh?
- 怎么了 - 真是个奇怪的地方
- What? - Strange places.
我喜欢晚上的医院
I like hospitals at night.
他们完全属于自己
They're...completely their own thing.
这说的通吗
Does that make any sense?
当然
Yeah.
晚餐愉快
Enjoy your dinner.
这地方真不错
是的 我好喜欢来这里
你真古怪
那些沉迷网络不接触现实世界的人才古怪
想进去吗
想 怎么进去
从这爬到屋顶然后你就可以进去了
懂了 蜘蛛侠
- 你确定 - 是的
早上好
Ah, morning.
能不能一起喝杯咖啡
Any chance of a coffee?
把你捡到的钱投进去
Put that euro you found in there.
闭路电视上发现什么吗
Anything off the bar CCTV?
没有
No.
我搜索了我的记忆之屋 但是找不到
I tried that house of memories thing. Didn't work.
- 没有吗 -没有 在洗衣房迷路了
- No? - No. Got lost in the laundry room.
可能这有点吓到你
This might come as a bit of a shock to you,
但是我想我们的室内装潢
but I suspect our inner landscapes
应该大有不同
differ quite significantly.
但愿吧
Well, I hope so.
不如哪天你告诉我你的房子吧
Will you tell me about your house one day?
不
No.
不想都知道
Thought not.
快来
这里好臭
我们当时就住在附近 这里以前是一个酒库
看 那有张床
别太兴奋 走了一夜我好累
那是什么
一些旧冰柜
会不会有酒啊
甚至香槟
来庆祝我逃离我爸爸
为什么他那么讨厌我
你非得知道答案吗
他会报警吗
不会啦
首先他会怪我妈妈然后再报警
那可不行 你妈妈很可爱的
为什么她要和他结婚
那是什么
What's that?
他又来了
He's in there again.
有两个人
There's two of them.
摄像头一直在拍让・克劳德 根本看不到他们
那袖子上是什么 截屏下来
看镜头 看镜头
Look into the camera. Look into the camera.
你还好吗 先生
- 他被绑起来了 我不能松绑 - 你是谁
- 快走 - 我们要帮你
快离开这里
- 快报警 - 这就是为什么人需要手机
- 你们帮不了我 - 这没信号
到外面去找信号
给我们看你们的脸 给我们看你们的脸
Show us your face. Show us your face.
或者离开这
Or get out of there.
一定有人在监视你们
You know who else must be watching.
- 离开这 - 她去求助了
我不能丢下你 先生
莉亚在报警 会没事的
天啊
一个女孩失踪了 莉亚・马丁
这夹克的样式和她妈妈描述的一样
她和男朋友私奔了 西蒙・马西尔
他们有电话吗
他没有 她关机了所以她父亲找不到她
我们搜查了他们的居住地并询问了他们的朋友
继续搜查任何能让我们知道他们位置的消息
两个孩子
Two kids?
也许这会让真理杀手相形见绌
Maybe that will take the shine off the Truth Terrorist.
还是联系不上他
不好意思
Excuse me.
也许他又换服务器了
也许...
他是很小心地策划这件事的
不会轻易放弃的
很好 你收到这个新电话了
Good, you received a new phone.
你不想让警察听到
You don't want the cops listening.
这是你和我之间的谈话
These conversations are just for you and me.
我真是受宠若惊
I suppose I'm flattered.
那么
So?
你想让我把什么公布于众
What do you want me to tell the world?
问我个问题
Ask me a question.
好的
All right.
信号断后发生了什么事
What happened when the feed went dead?
其他人都是谁还有为什么你要挂断线
Who were the other people and why did you go offline?
下个问题
Next question.
那个人还活着吗
Is the man still alive?
是的
Yes.
为什么有五个真相
Why five truths?
这之后你会停手吗
What, are you just going to stop after that?
现在说这个还为时尚早
We are a long way from that point still.
你到底想怎样
What do you want?
你做这一切是为了什么
What is all this getting you?
为了接近真相
Closer to the truth.
我们都离真相越来越近了
We're all getting closer to the truth.
那么...接下来你要做什么
So...what's next?
我手里的那个老人还有救
The old man I'm holding can be saved.
用你的报纸告诉大家
Use your newspaper to tell people that.
他还有救
He can be saved.
怎么救
How?
苏菲
hey, Sophie.
最近怎么样
How's it going?
还不错
Fine.
很好
Good.
我爸爸在吗
Is my dad here?
他出海了
He had to go to sea,
他...买了艘新船所以他...
he's, erm, got a new ship that he had to...
我们去那边坐会
Come sit with me a minute.
你不能每次和你妈妈吵架
You can't keep turning up like this
都跑来我这里
every time you have a row with your mother.
我们之间有监护的规定
There's a custody order.
因为格蕾丝根本不想见到我
Because Grace doesn't want to see me.
你要理解她
You have to understand her too.
她觉得我更偏爱你
She feels I prefer you to the little ones.
我喜欢那种感觉
I'd love to have that feeling.
汤姆只有四岁
Tom's only four.
洁米才九个月大
Jamie's only nine months.
和他们比你是个大姑娘了 几乎是成人了
Compared to them you're a big girl. Almost a grown-up.
我可以在这过夜
I can stay the night though,
这不违反监护规定
that's not against the custody order.
事实上 今晚是汤姆的生日宴会
The thing is, it's Tom's birthday party this evening
并且格蕾丝一家人都要在这过夜
and Grace's family are all staying the night.
我们没有多余的房间了
We don't have room.
好啦 我知道你能处理好和你妈的关系
Come on, I know you can sort things out with your mother.
需要我送你回去吗
You want me to drive you back?
有什么需要就给我打电话 好吗
Call me if you need anything, eh?
有个小男孩在牧场里玩
And there was a little boy in the field.
他看上去很可爱 但不会说英语
Ever so sweet, he was. Didn't have a word of English.
你说的妈妈是...
And you said the mum...?
她非常奇怪
She was really strange.
看上去好像有人刚打过她
And it looked as though someone had just hit her.
之后 当我经过时 门是开着的
And later, when I walked past, the door was open
但是没有人在那
but there was nobody there.
我不想给他们找麻烦
I don't want to get them into trouble.
"宽以待人"是我的格言
"Live and let live" is my motto.
我也是  除非他们是托特纳姆的球迷
Mine too. Well, unless they're Tottenham.
我真的很担心他们
I'm really worried about them.
这不对劲 那里肯定发生了什么
It's just not right, what goes on in there.
抱歉 姑娘 我们打烊了
Sorry, love, I'm closed.
你站在那里做什么
Why are you standing there?
关你什么事
What's it to you?
你都湿透了 一定很冷
You look cold and wet.
那是因为这雨天太冷了
That's because it's freezing and raining.
你不能站在这里
You can't stand there.
你脸上是雨水还是你在哭
Is that rain on your face or are you crying?
我正准备泡杯茶
I was just about to have a cup of tea.
如何你愿意 可以给你来一杯
There's enough for two if you want one.
抱歉 姑娘
Sorry, love.
放弃了吗
Given up, eh?
- 进展如何 - 很好
- How's it going? - Good.
虽然只工作了八年 但这次我确信
It's only been eight years but I'm confident this time.
就我而言是五年
Five in my case.
不错
Well done.
孩子们有消息吗
没有
每次他有动作 我都能更了解他
我已经开始明白他的规则了
你觉得他遵守规则吗
是的
Yes.
我们都遵守规则
We all follow rules.
那只狗和孩子们不在他的计划中
The dog and the kids he hadn't planned on.
- 它抛弃了他 - 我知道他的感受
- It threw him. - I know how he feels.
是啊 他让一个人又重操旧业了
Yeah. It'd drive a man back to cigarettes.
你的法语有进步
Your French is getting better.
- 谢谢 - 你要走吗
- Merci. - You're leaving?
是的
Yep.
我和你一起走
I'll come down with you.
别一整晚盯在这 去睡会吧
等我取下东西
I'll get my stuff.
晚安
Bonne nuit.
我受邀去巴黎工作 永久性的
I've been asked to go to Paris, permanently.
比起加莱谁能不选择去巴黎
Well, who could possibly choose Paris over Calais?
你喜欢爱丽丝
You like Elise?
- 怎么看出来的 - 任何地方
- In what sense? - In any sense.
她是个好警察
She's a good cop.
是我合作过的最好的
Best I ever worked with.
当然 不是谁都能理解她的
Not everybody gets her, of course.
- 晚安 - 晚安
- Night. - Night.
车不错
Nice car.
恭喜你得到巴黎的工作
Congratulations on the Paris job.
我还没有告诉爱丽丝
I haven't spoke to Elise about it yet.
先别告诉任何人
Keep it to yourself for now.
我这只有绿茶
I've only got green tea.
很好了
That's great.
你为什么哭
Why were you crying?
家庭琐事
Family stuff.
常有的事
That happens.
我不能回家
I can't go home.
如果你愿意就呆在这里
Stay here if you want.
- 这里 - 你可以睡那边的床
- Here? - You can sleep on the bed in there.
这只有一间卧室
There's only one bedroom.
我可以睡我的瑜伽垫上
I sleep on my yoga mat.
真的 你睡床吧
Really, take the bed.
最近都没人用过所以床单很干净
It hasn't been used recently so the sheets are clean.
也许我妈现在会有点失眠
Maybe my mum will lose a bit of sleep now.
菲利普 菲利普
Philippe! Philippe!
他很冷
他又在线上了
He's back online.
老人在冬天一般会怎样
What happens to old people in winter?
救他
他们能救他